#### KADIDIA ZAMA

The Woodlands, TX • kadidia.zama@gmail.com • (202) 615-2720 • linkedin.com/in/kadidia-zama https://kadidia-zama.netlifv.app

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Data Analyst with experience in the Logistics, Professional Services, and Healthcare industries. By utilizing proven Excel, Tableau, and SQL skills, excelled in gathering, analyzing, interpreting, and presenting crucial findings from all types and sizes of datasets. Bringing attention to detail, love for data, passion for visual storytelling, and productive in both self-managed and distributed team environments. Enthusiastic about technologies, learning new trends, and continued professional growth.

#### **SKILLS**

- MS Excel
- Data Cleaning
- Data Analysis
- BI Tools
- Tableau
- SQL

- Data Management
- Critical Thinking
- Curiosity
- Linear Algebra & Calculus

- Adaptability
- Communication
- Problem-Solving
- Presentation

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### Data Analyst | Freelancer/Contractor

Jan 2023- Present

- Perform data analysis in an educational environment.
- Manipulate, clean, and analyze data using Excel, and SQL.
- Corrected any data entry error to prevent later issues such as duplication or data degradation.
- Utilize historical data sets and planned product changes to forecast business trends.
- Create visual reports using PivotChart & Tableau.
- Day-to-day communication with partners to agree on requirements.
- Successfully interpreted data and presented reports to clients to draw conclusions for managerial action and strategy.

# Data Analyst | Coursework & Projects

Oct 2022-Jan 2023

## Superstore-Subset

- Used the Superstore-Subset data to analyze the most profitable customers and most profitable products for a selected order date.
- Build a dynamic visualization dashboard in Tableau to show the most profitable customers, products, and monthly profitability.
- Recommended solutions to increase store profitability.

#### **Movie Recommendation Engine**

- Used the IMDB's database to analysis on the ranks of movie genres based on their average ratings from 2000 to 2010 using excel to build an improved movie recommendation system.
- Saved an average of 17 minutes on move selection relative to the previous methodology.
- Build visualizations in Excel to show how rating changes and how the model performs over time.

#### **Business Analyst** | Coursework & Projects **Amazon Test Case**

Summer/Fall 1018

- Provided cost-effective and profitable meals and catering services for up to 500 plus employees, including self-checkout, administered cashier services, and a mobile app to order meals online.
- Analyzed risks and constraints to designing process flow for external interactions, menu planning, online orders, cashier system, and inventory.
- Built Use Case Models, Activity Diagrams, and Process Flows and worked in Waterfall and Agile Scrum environments.

#### Hilton Online Booking System

Gathered and translated high-level requirements (EPIC) into well-defined system scope, project milestones, software, hardware, and support resources.

- Performed GAP analysis of the existing paper-based system and recommended changes for conversion to a web-based one.
- Analyzed high-level requirements and developed business cases.
- Participated in meetings such as Daily Scrum, Sprint Planning, and Sprint Retrospective to ensure alignment of objectives and timely resolution.

#### Financial Analyst and Account Payables Supervisor | Secor – Group | Washington, DC 2007-2016

- Reviewed financial statement, and completed cost and revenue analysis. Creating forecasting tracking and management reporting systems to improve the availability and accuracy of financial data, triggering a 13% increase in accuracy.
- Evaluated the efficiency and effectiveness of accounting processes, made recommendations to optimize them, and chose the appropriate costing approach to use in any given business situation.
- Served as Subject Matter Expert during Accounts Payable System Automation. Process leadership and system adoption eliminated service delivery gaps and human errors while increasing its organizational capacity to process, approve and document high-volume invoices. Completed the project before schedule, recovered 28K in savings due to eliminating errors, and reduced total invoice input time by 80%.
- Developed and maintained strong vendor relationships, contracts, and negotiated payment terms. Served the company's best interest by satisfactorily negotiating repayment schedules and executing a mutually beneficial payment plan across multiple vendors during a state of financial crisis.
- Developed and implemented new processes to continually improve the effectiveness and efficiency of the department and increase staff accountability. Spearheaded the implementation and staff training.

#### **EDUCATION**

MS in Healthcare Administration   Southern New Hampshire University	Anticipated March 2023
'	•
Master of Business Administration   University of the District of Columbia	December 2007
Master of Business Administration   University of Ouagadougou   Burkina Faso	September 2002
	•
CERTIFICATIONS	
Tableau Certificate   Udemy	Dec 2022
Microsoft Excel – Data Analysis with Excel Pivot Tables   Udemy	Nov 2022

Microsoft Excel - Data Analysis with Excel Pivot Tables | Udemy Project Management Professional (PMP) | PMI **Business Analyst for IT Professionals | TSCER** 

May 2022 December 2018

#### LANGUAGES

French | Native or Bilingual English | Fluent